<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>risc-v on The world beyond Linux</title>
    <link>https://worldbeyondlinux.be/tags/risc-v/</link>
    <description>Recent content in risc-v on The world beyond Linux</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 13:37:07 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://worldbeyondlinux.be/tags/risc-v/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>GPIO on the MangoPi MQ-Pro</title>
      <link>https://worldbeyondlinux.be/posts/gpio-on-the-mango-pi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 13:37:07 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldbeyondlinux.be/posts/gpio-on-the-mango-pi/</guid>
      <description>One of the last aspects I wanted to explore and get working on my MangoPi MQ-Pro. For this experiment, like my previous endeavor trying out Bluetooth on my MangoPi MQ-Pro, I used the Ubuntu 22.10 RISC-V image for the SiPeed LicheeRV Dock image.
No extra configuration is needed to get GPIO working with this image on the MangoPi MQ-Pro. I tried out three different ways of accessing the GPIO pins; using legacy sysfs-based access, using the userspace GPIO driver, and lastly using lgpio from Python.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up Bluetooth on the MangoPi MQ-Pro, and testing it out with a Bluetooth access point</title>
      <link>https://worldbeyondlinux.be/posts/bluetooth-on-the-mango-pi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 17:17:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldbeyondlinux.be/posts/bluetooth-on-the-mango-pi/</guid>
      <description>I received my MangoPi MQ-Pro a few months ago, and was very eager to test out all the hardware which I use the most on SBC&amp;rsquo;s. Bluetooth is not one of the features I use a lot on SBC&amp;rsquo;s. But after having tested out a lot of operating systems and hardware features of the board, I decided to also try and see what the status of Bluetooth on the board was.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring non-Linux Based Operating Systems on Allwinner D1</title>
      <link>https://worldbeyondlinux.be/posts/exploring-non-linux-oses-on-d1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 16:28:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldbeyondlinux.be/posts/exploring-non-linux-oses-on-d1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction As of writing this article, there are a few choices of operating systems to choose from for the Allwinner D1. In the future, more choices will probably become available. In this article we will take a closer look into FreeBSD and xv6 for the Allwinner D1. I will use a MangoPi MQ-Pro to test these operating systems.
FreeBSD For many people, FreeBSD won&amp;rsquo;t need an introduction. FreeBSD is a free and open-source Unix-like operating system first released in 1993.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running x86_64 Software on RISC-V Using Box64</title>
      <link>https://worldbeyondlinux.be/posts/running-x86-64-software-on-riscv-using-box64/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2022 18:44:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldbeyondlinux.be/posts/running-x86-64-software-on-riscv-using-box64/</guid>
      <description>In this post I will give an overview on how a ran some software compiled for x86_64 on my RISC-V SBC, a MangoPi MQ-Pro. We will be using an awesome piece of software called Box64. Basically this software runs x86_64 binaries through an emulator, but with a twist; it uses the native versions of some &amp;ldquo;system&amp;rdquo; libraries, like libc, libm, SDL, and OpenGL, like described in the README of the project:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Use a Raspberry Pi Instead of a USB Console Cable</title>
      <link>https://worldbeyondlinux.be/posts/how-to-use-a-pi-instead-of-a-usb-console-cable/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 11:39:44 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldbeyondlinux.be/posts/how-to-use-a-pi-instead-of-a-usb-console-cable/</guid>
      <description>As the title says, this article will be about using a Raspberry Pi SBC (whatever model), instead of a USB Console Cable to debug another SBC, router, microcontroller&amp;hellip; The need for this came when I received my MangoPi MQ-Pro, I wanted to try different operating systems for this SBC, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t have access to a USB Console Cable, at least not one that was 3.3V tolerant. I wanted to have access to the serial console because a lot of OS images for the MangoPi, at the time of writing this article, didn&amp;rsquo;t have HDMI drivers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
